<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Mr Nibbles Forever &#8211; Epic Shrimp</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/mr-nibbles-forever/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>The best things come in small packages!</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 11:48:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.5.3</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Mr Nibbles Forever – Launched on Steam</title>
		<link>/mr-nibbles-forever/mr-nibbles-forever-launched-on-steam/</link>
		<comments>/mr-nibbles-forever/mr-nibbles-forever-launched-on-steam/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 08:27:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Cann]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Mr Nibbles Forever]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=5830</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Yesterday marked the culmination of many months of hard work, we released Mr Nibbles Forever to the Steam store! Following the launch on mobile last year and the rather disappointing lack of players of the game I had a deep and meaningful discussion with myself and came to the conclusion that the problem wasn&#8217;t the<p><a href="/mr-nibbles-forever/mr-nibbles-forever-launched-on-steam/">Continue Reading &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday marked the culmination of many months of hard work, we <a href="http://store.steampowered.com/app/448050/">released Mr Nibbles Forever to the Steam store</a>!</p>
<p>Following the launch on mobile last year and the rather disappointing lack of players of the game I had a deep and meaningful discussion with myself and came to the conclusion that the problem wasn&#8217;t the game it was my ability to market it correctly. </p>
<p><a href="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/1.png"><img src="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/1-300x169.png" alt="1" width="300" height="169" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-5900" /></a></p>
<p>The game reviewed well and the people that played it seemed to enjoy the game but unfortunately due to both my lack of interest and lack of ability to push the game very hard I was unable to get too many eyeballs on the game.</p>
<p>I decided that what I needed was someone to take all the stuff that I dont like doing, namely the marketing and selling of the game, so I could concentrate on developing the thing.</p>
<p>So I decided to contact a few publishers, one of which (<a href="http://blackshellmedia.com/">Black Shell Media</a>) decided to publish the game on PC. </p>
<p><a href="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/4.png"><img src="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/4-300x169.png" alt="4" width="300" height="169" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-5902" /></a></p>
<p>The experience with BSM has been great, they have helped me all along the way with design suggestions and VERY helpful pre-launch beta test groups and feedback. Its felt more like a family with other developers regularly meeting on Discord to discuss their game and the games industry in general. </p>
<p>So time will tell now if my strategy of partnering with a publisher was worth it. So far I have really enjoyed the process and not worrying about the marketing too much is definitely something im happy about.</p>
<p>Anyways, if you havent already, now is a great time to checkout Mr Nibbles Forever on Steam: <a href="http://store.steampowered.com/app/448050/">http://store.steampowered.com/app/448050/</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/mr-nibbles-forever/mr-nibbles-forever-launched-on-steam/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mr Nibbles Forever &#8211; Now on Apple App Store!</title>
		<link>/mr-nibbles-forever/mr-nibbles-forever-now-on-apple-app-store/</link>
		<comments>/mr-nibbles-forever/mr-nibbles-forever-now-on-apple-app-store/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2015 09:33:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Cann]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Mr Nibbles Forever]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Projects]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2d]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Game]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nibbles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[release]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.mikecann.co.uk/?p=5737</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Weeeee! Finally we got approval from Apple on Friday last week and after a frustrating 3 hours of waiting for apple to push a button it launched! You can grab it from the App Store on your device or simply follow this link: https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mr-nibbles-forever/id958818922?mt=8 Im so happy that its out the door, had a few<p><a href="/mr-nibbles-forever/mr-nibbles-forever-now-on-apple-app-store/">Continue Reading &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Weeeee! Finally we got approval from Apple on Friday last week and after a frustrating 3 hours of waiting for apple to push a button it launched!</p>
<p>You can grab it from the App Store on your device or simply follow this link: <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mr-nibbles-forever/id958818922?mt=8">https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mr-nibbles-forever/id958818922?mt=8</a></p>
<p>Im so happy that its out the door, had a few people play already and some have submitted some bugs which need to get fixed soon. </p>
<p>Im on holiday in Bali from Saturday for some much needed R&#038;R, but when I get back I hope to do a patch or two and if the traffic justifies it perhaps a content update.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/mr-nibbles-forever/mr-nibbles-forever-now-on-apple-app-store/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mr Nibbles Forever &#8211; Out now on Google Play</title>
		<link>/mr-nibbles-forever/mr-nibbles-forever-out-now-on-google-play/</link>
		<comments>/mr-nibbles-forever/mr-nibbles-forever-out-now-on-google-play/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2015 10:10:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Cann]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Mr Nibbles Forever]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=5809</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The title says it all! The game is now finally out on Google Play 🙂 https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=uk.co.mikecann.mrnibblesforever It took me much longer than I had originally expected when I started it back in January but im happy to say that no matter how it performs on the marketplace I feel as if I did it justice.<p><a href="/mr-nibbles-forever/mr-nibbles-forever-out-now-on-google-play/">Continue Reading &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The title says it all! The game is now finally out on Google Play <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> </p>
<p><a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=uk.co.mikecann.mrnibblesforever">https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=uk.co.mikecann.mrnibblesforever</a></p>
<p>It took me much longer than I had originally expected when I started it <a href="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/portfolio/mr-nibbles-forever-a-prototype/">back in January</a> but im happy to say that no matter how it performs on the marketplace I feel as if I did it justice. I tried hard not to get fed up towards the end of the project as I tend to and put the hard graft in to get the monetisation and gameplay right.</p>
<p>I missed the deadline for the iOS version today as its still waiting to be approved by Apple but im hoping it wont be too much longer. </p>
<p>After that I plan on doing an Amazon build of the game and perhaps a content pack or two depending if I get more than just a handful of players <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/mr-nibbles-forever/mr-nibbles-forever-out-now-on-google-play/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mr Nibbles Forever &#8211; The Final Beta (11)</title>
		<link>/mr-nibbles-forever/mr-nibbles-forever-the-final-beta-11/</link>
		<comments>/mr-nibbles-forever/mr-nibbles-forever-the-final-beta-11/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 10:52:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Cann]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Mr Nibbles Forever]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Projects]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bug fix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Game]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[indie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Update]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.mikecann.co.uk/?p=5718</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s been 3 weeks since the last update but lots has happened in that time. I have tried hard to stick to the plan I made for myself on the 21st of June. A quick recap: 20th – 26th July 1) Create game trailer and publish to landing page. 2) Contact media and other social<p><a href="/mr-nibbles-forever/mr-nibbles-forever-the-final-beta-11/">Continue Reading &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s been 3 weeks since the last update but lots has happened in that time. </p>
<p>I have tried hard to stick to the <a href="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/myprojects/mr-nibbles-forever-getting-it-done/">plan I made for myself on the 21st of June</a>. A quick recap:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>20th – 26th July</strong><br />
1) Create game trailer and publish to landing page.<br />
2) Contact media and other social networks, point to landing page.</p>
<p><strong>27th July – 2nd August</strong><br />
1) Final bug fix and polish pass.<br />
2) Contact more media and social networks.</p>
<p><strong>3rd – 9th August</strong><br />
1) Release Android version of the game.<br />
2) Contact media and social networks.</p></blockquote>
<p>So the first task was to make a trailer for the game which I managed to do:</p>
<p><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vO6mjWDz5RM" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>Its not perfect but im pretty happy with how it turned out with only a weeks worth of work and a very limited knowledge of After Effects and Game Trailer making in general.</p>
<p>After finishing the trailer I had a week of bug fixing and polish before <a href="http://gamecloud.net.au/features/perth-gaming/playup-perth-sk-games-after-dark-5-gaming-overload">I took the game to Playup Perth,</a> an indie games meetup here in Perth. </p>
<p>The meeting went well, people enjoyed playing the game. It gave me a few ideas for expansions in the future and hinted at some small things which I could implement immediately. So heres a list of the things I managed to <a href="https://trello.com/b/Ic11WQzF/mr-nibbles-forever">fix and implement over the past few weeks, some 40 hours</a> of work:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Untitled-2.png"><img src="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Untitled-2-684x1024.png" alt="Untitled-2" width="684" height="1024" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-5721" /></a></p>
<p>Oh that reminds me, we also have a new icon for the game designed by Woody:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/icon1024.png"><img src="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/icon1024.png" alt="icon1024" width="1024" height="1024" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5722" /></a></p>
<p>It looks great in my opinion, he did a stellar job there. </p>
<p>We also have a new company logo for Epic Shrimp:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/epic-shrimp-logo.png"><img src="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/epic-shrimp-logo.png" alt="epic shrimp logo" width="975" height="912" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5723" /></a></p>
<p>This one is by my friend and ex-colleague Alan Mac, great work there Alan, even if you did manage to sneak in your little trademark in there (points to anyone who notices).</p>
<p>So the time for the release is almost here. So long as this new beta for the game looks okay then I hope to send some emails out to reporters to give the game a play and hopefully a review then in a week or two I hope to push the game to the store! </p>
<p>As usual if you are interested in testing the game you can use this public beta link: https://play.google.com/apps/testing/uk.co.mikecann.mrnibblesforever﻿ or send me an email for the iOS version and ill add you as a beta tester: mike.cann@gmail.com</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/mr-nibbles-forever/mr-nibbles-forever-the-final-beta-11/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mr Nibbles Forever &#8211; Pre Release 10</title>
		<link>/mr-nibbles-forever/mr-nibbles-forever-pre-release-10/</link>
		<comments>/mr-nibbles-forever/mr-nibbles-forever-pre-release-10/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2015 07:59:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Cann]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mr Nibbles Forever]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Projects]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2d]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Game]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mr nibbles forever]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.mikecann.co.uk/?p=5706</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Its been almost exactly a week since the last developmental release of Mr Nibbles Forever. According to the plan this week should have been about implementing the landing page and gathering feedback from people, as I managed to get the landing page sorted in the first week I decided to spend the time developing the<p><a href="/mr-nibbles-forever/mr-nibbles-forever-pre-release-10/">Continue Reading &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Its been almost exactly a week since the last developmental release of Mr Nibbles Forever. According to <a href="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/myprojects/mr-nibbles-forever-getting-it-done/">the plan</a> this week should have been about implementing the landing page and gathering feedback from people, as I managed to get the landing page sorted in the first week I decided to spend the time developing the game instead.</p>
<p>So this week I have concentrated on decreasing the loading times for the game. On my Nexus 7 the loading time was about one minute which is way too long. The main reason for the load times is the way I construct the levels. </p>
<p>As mentioned <a href="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/myprojects/mr-nibbles-forever-prototype-2/">way back in my second post</a> for the game the levels are made up of pre-defined chunks:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/2015-07-12_15-24-52.png"><img src="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/2015-07-12_15-24-52-1024x589.png" alt="2015-07-12_15-24-52" width="940" height="541" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-5709" /></a></p>
<p>These chunks are individual scenes. I did it this way because Unity doesn&#8217;t support nested prefabs and I wanted the ability to change properties of some of the elements of the levels as I was developing. The problem with this however is that to construct the levels I must first load the chunk scene, then extract its contents and build a level.</p>
<p>Unity&#8217;s scene loading system is very slow and causes the game to pause and stutter if you try to do it at run time. As a result I put a &#8220;build&#8221; button into the editor which runs through a small script which loads all the chunks into a specially built &#8220;Release&#8221; scene:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/2015-07-12_15-31-15.png"><img src="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/2015-07-12_15-31-15.png" alt="2015-07-12_15-31-15" width="583" height="247" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5710" /></a></p>
<p>So now all the chunks are available in one single scene at startup removing the scene loading issue while the game is running. This is great but it does now mean that the initial load of the game is gigantic as it has to load 80 chunks with thousands of game objects at startup. The result is the game takes a minute to load.</p>
<p>To solve this problem I modified my &#8220;build&#8221; process so now instead of simply importing the chunk scenes it also processes them a little bit. One common technique in optomising game performance is to use object pooling to reduce the amount of new objects that are created at runtime.</p>
<p>I know that the levels are going to have large numbers of certain types of objects such as spiders, nibbles and level tiles, so what I decided to do was record the unique properties for each instance of the objects such as their position, rotation, sprite type etc. I could then delete those objects from each chunk. </p>
<p>Now when a chunk is used in a level, it simply requests an existing instance of that object type from a global pool, then sets the unique properties on the object such as position and rotation.</p>
<p>The result of all that work is that the load times have been cut in half. So now just 30 seconds on my 2012 Nexus 7. There is probably more room for improvements there but considering that the deadline for the game is coming up, im happy with it for now.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/2015-07-12_15-47-42.png"><img src="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/2015-07-12_15-47-42-1024x419.png" alt="2015-07-12_15-47-42" width="940" height="385" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-5711" /></a></p>
<p>In addition to that performance work, I also had a little more time to work through a few other small bugs and one more feature. </p>
<p>A few people had suggested to me that it would be good to add a &#8220;remove ads&#8221; option to the game as many people would be happy to remove the ads for a small fee. Well it wasnt a huge amount of work to do it so I put it in. </p>
<p><a href="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/2015-07-12_15-50-59.png"><img src="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/2015-07-12_15-50-59.png" alt="2015-07-12_15-50-59" width="977" height="693" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5712" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/2015-07-12_15-51-30.png"><img src="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/2015-07-12_15-51-30.png" alt="2015-07-12_15-51-30" width="940" height="742" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5713" /></a></p>
<p>So now, you no longer need to watch an ad when you want to start or restart a challenge:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/2015-07-12_15-53-33.png"><img src="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/2015-07-12_15-53-33.png" alt="2015-07-12_15-53-33" width="970" height="726" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5714" /></a></p>
<p>Well that&#8217;s it for this week. The plan for next week is to plan the game trailer and to experiment with full-screen post process effects again which will hopefully add a whole lot more to the individual visual aspect of each outfit. </p>
<p>As per usual if you are interested in testing the game on Android then join the community page: https://plus.google.com/u/0/communities/100690884724496136044 or for iOS email me: mike.cann@gmail.com</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/mr-nibbles-forever/mr-nibbles-forever-pre-release-10/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mr Nibbles Forever &#8211; Pre Release 9</title>
		<link>/mr-nibbles-forever/mr-nibbles-forever-pre-release-9/</link>
		<comments>/mr-nibbles-forever/mr-nibbles-forever-pre-release-9/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2015 05:08:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Cann]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Mr Nibbles Forever]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2d]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Game]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mr nibbles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unity3d]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.mikecann.co.uk/?p=5670</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Well its been almost two weeks since I declared the (tough) scheduled plan for the release of Mr Nibbles Forever. In it I planned that last week was to be: 22nd-28th June 1) Design landing page for the game. This is important as I will need a place to put the trailer and to send<p><a href="/mr-nibbles-forever/mr-nibbles-forever-pre-release-9/">Continue Reading &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well its been almost two weeks since <a href="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/myprojects/mr-nibbles-forever-getting-it-done/">I declared the (tough) scheduled plan</a> for the release of Mr Nibbles Forever. In it I planned that last week was to be:</p>
<blockquote><p>22nd-28th June<br />
1) Design landing page for the game. This is important as I will need a place to put the trailer and to send people who are interested in the game. I have read several good resources on how this page should look. Some examples of other landing pages are: http://www.pixelprospector.com/list-of-websites-and-blogs-from-game-developers/. Once landing page is designed, run it pass some designer friends for help improving it.<br />
2) Pester people for feedback on Alpha 8. I need to get some real-world feedback for the game so I can fix bugs and improve the polish for release 9.<br />
3) Contact some marketing people for help and advice.</p></blockquote>
<p>Well I managed to do 1) and 2) but I decided that I didnt need to do 3) just yet, instead I made do with the excellent advice on these two pages:</p>
<p>http://vgamemarketing.com/<br />
http://www.pixelprospector.com/</p>
<p>I may go back to 3) in a week or two if I need to.</p>
<p>As for 1) well I decided after an hour or two of messing around in Photoshop that it would be easier and faster to just buy an off-the-shelf WordPress theme and adjust that to my needs as I was intimately familiar with WordPress. The theme I chose was <a href="http://themeforest.net/item/grizzly-responsive-app-showcase-corporate/1546240">Grizzly from Wegrass</a>:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/2015-07-03_07-33-47.png"><img src="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/2015-07-03_07-33-47-300x231.png" alt="2015-07-03_07-33-47" width="300" height="231" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-5671" /></a></p>
<p>It seemed to have all the features I needed for now and was responsive which is super important these days. </p>
<p>The next issue was what name should I call the &#8220;company&#8221;. Up until now I had been going with the name &#8220;Nibblers&#8221; as that was the name that &#8220;Mr Nibbles&#8221; was published under too. &#8220;Nibblers&#8221; however is very specific to Mr Nibbles games and if I wanted to do non-nibbles games in the future it would sound a little odd so I needed a new name.</p>
<p>After much head scratching I decided I wanted to base the name around my favorite animal the Mantis Shrimp. If you dont know what it is, then checkout <a href="http://theoatmeal.com/comics/mantis_shrimp">the oatmeal&#8217;s excellent bit on it</a>. The problem was that mantisshrimp.com is taken, also its difficult to tell someone the domain, as they either dont know how to spell it or are confused as to how many S&#8217;es there are in the middle.</p>
<p>So in the end I decided to go with something that was related and instead use the Mantis Shrimp in the logo. So I went with&#8230;. Epic Shrimp:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/2015-07-03_07-41-32.png"><img src="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/2015-07-03_07-41-32-1024x728.png" alt="2015-07-03_07-41-32" width="940" height="668" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-5672" /></a></p>
<p>The site is still very much under development but at least I now have a good landing page for Mr Nibbles, Ectoplasm and Mr Nibbles Forever:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/2015-07-03_07-43-27.png"><img src="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/2015-07-03_07-43-27.png" alt="2015-07-03_07-43-27" width="958" height="879" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5673" /></a></p>
<p>So although last week was supposed to just be design, I decided to go the full-hog and implement too, which means that I have one more week free for development.</p>
<p>Speaking of development, this week we <a href="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/myprojects/mr-nibbles-forever-getting-it-done/">supposed to be a bug-fixing and polish pass</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>29th June – 5th July<br />
1) Do bug-fixing and polish pass of the game. Push release 9 of the game to people for testing and feedback.</p></blockquote>
<p>Its true that I did indeed fix some minor bugs&#8230;</p>
<p><a href="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/2015-07-03_07-46-39.png"><img src="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/2015-07-03_07-46-39.png" alt="2015-07-03_07-46-39" width="283" height="816" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5674" /></a></p>
<p>&#8230; this week was mostly dedicated to improving the high scores system in the game. </p>
<p>As a result of some feedback from people I decided that the game needs to be more in-your-face about the competitive aspect. Hopefully this will encourage people to return more often so that they can try to get higher up the leader boards. </p>
<p>I was unsatisfied with my current GameCentre and GoolgePlayServices implementation of the highscores so I decided to roll my own using my Parse.com experience. So now you will notice that next to the high-scores button that every each play you are given your daily rank:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/2015-07-03_07-49-39.png"><img src="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/2015-07-03_07-49-39-1024x772.png" alt="2015-07-03_07-49-39" width="940" height="709" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-5675" /></a></p>
<p>Clicking the button will show you the top ranked players in each category:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/2015-07-03_07-51-51.png"><img src="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/2015-07-03_07-51-51-1024x768.png" alt="2015-07-03_07-51-51" width="940" height="705" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-5676" /></a></p>
<p>You will notice that your name is &#8220;???&#8221; until you set your name:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/2015-07-03_07-54-31.png"><img src="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/2015-07-03_07-54-31-1024x763.png" alt="2015-07-03_07-54-31" width="940" height="700" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-5677" /></a></p>
<p>Once done, all your old and new scores will now be saved under that name, this works across devices too. </p>
<p><a href="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/2015-07-03_07-55-33.png"><img src="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/2015-07-03_07-55-33-1024x773.png" alt="2015-07-03_07-55-33" width="940" height="710" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-5678" /></a></p>
<p>I am also experimenting around with having a button next to any high score which also has a saved replay. </p>
<p><a href="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/2015-07-03_07-57-26.png"><img src="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/2015-07-03_07-57-26-1024x763.png" alt="2015-07-03_07-57-26" width="940" height="700" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-5679" /></a></p>
<p>Clicking the button will open Everyplay and show the recorded run for that highscore, which I think is pretty cool!</p>
<p>Well that&#8217;s it for now, this weekend I am going to be extremely busy on something else (more in another blog post soon) so I wont have any more time, but hopefully next week will either be more bug fixing and polish and getting more feedback on the game. </p>
<p>As usual if you would like to try the game and are on iOS then just email me: mike.cann@gmail.com, or if you are Android then join this page: <a href="https://plus.google.com/u/0/communities/100690884724496136044">https://plus.google.com/u/0/communities/100690884724496136044</a></p>
<p>Until next week!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/mr-nibbles-forever/mr-nibbles-forever-pre-release-9/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mr Nibbles Forever &#8211; Getting it done</title>
		<link>/mr-nibbles-forever/mr-nibbles-forever-getting-it-done/</link>
		<comments>/mr-nibbles-forever/mr-nibbles-forever-getting-it-done/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 07:30:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Cann]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Mr Nibbles Forever]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[goals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plan]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.mikecann.co.uk/?p=5608</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I talked about this in my last blog post but Mr Nibbles Forever is starting to take shape now. The features have been ready for some time now and the the last update saw 95% of the game&#8217;s artwork go in. Basically the game itself its pretty much there apart from bug fixes and polish.<p><a href="/mr-nibbles-forever/mr-nibbles-forever-getting-it-done/">Continue Reading &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I talked about this in my <a href="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/myprojects/mr-nibbles-alpha-8/">last blog post</a> but Mr Nibbles Forever is starting to take shape now. The features have been ready for some time now and the the last update saw 95% of the game&#8217;s artwork go in. Basically the game itself its pretty much there apart from bug fixes and polish.</p>
<p>Anyone who has worked with indie games will tell you that making the game is the easy bit, its all the rest that is hard. Its that phase that I am now entering into. There is much that I need to do before I can release the game so I thought I would try to get some goals for the next few weeks so I can plan out the next series of steps and hopefully it will help others who are in a similar situation.</p>
<h2>22nd-28th June</h2>
<p>1) Design landing page for the game. This is important as I will need a place to put the trailer and to send people who are interested in the game. I have read several good resources on how this page should look. Some examples of other landing pages are: http://www.pixelprospector.com/list-of-websites-and-blogs-from-game-developers/. Once landing page is designed, run it pass some designer friends for help improving it.<br />
2) Pester people for feedback on Alpha 8. I need to get some real-world feedback for the game so I can fix bugs and improve the polish for release 9.<br />
3) Contact some marketing people for help and advice.</p>
<h2>29th June &#8211; 5th July</h2>
<p>1) Do bug-fixing and polish pass of the game. Push release 9 of the game to people for testing and feedback.</p>
<h2>6th &#8211; 12th July</h2>
<p>1) Implement landing page design.<br />
3) Gather feedback from release 9 of the game </p>
<h2>13th &#8211; 19th July</h2>
<p>1) Do bug-fixing and polish pass of the game. Push release 10 of the game to people for testing and feedback.<br />
2) Research and plan the teaser trailer.<br />
3) Construct Press Kit</p>
<h2>20th &#8211; 26th July</h2>
<p>1) Create game trailer and publish to landing page.<br />
2) Contact media and other social networks, point to landing page.</p>
<h2>27th July &#8211; 2nd August</h2>
<p>1) Final bug fix and polish pass.<br />
2) Contact more media and social networks.</p>
<h2>3rd &#8211; 9th August</h2>
<p>1) Release Android version of the game.<br />
2) Contact media and social networks.</p>
<h2>10th &#8211; 16th August</h2>
<p>1) Release iOS version of the game.<br />
2) Contact media and social networks</p>
<p>Well that&#8217;s the plan anyways. We will see if its fee sable over the coming weeks. Ill try to stick to it where I can. Given that I can stick to it then hopefully the game should be released in 6-weeks!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/mr-nibbles-forever/mr-nibbles-forever-getting-it-done/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mr Nibbles Alpha 8</title>
		<link>/mr-nibbles-forever/mr-nibbles-alpha-8/</link>
		<comments>/mr-nibbles-forever/mr-nibbles-alpha-8/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 00:21:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Cann]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Mr Nibbles Forever]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Audio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Game]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ios]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unity]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.mikecann.co.uk/?p=5596</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Well its been exactly 95 days since my last Alpha release of my mobile game Mr Nibbles Forever which is far too long. I apologise to people who have been asking me for a new version. I took on a few paid freelance projects a few months ago and they took up a whole bunch<p><a href="/mr-nibbles-forever/mr-nibbles-alpha-8/">Continue Reading &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well its been exactly <a href="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/myprojects/mr-nibbles-forever/mr-nibbles-forever-alpha-7/">95 days since my last Alpha release</a> of my mobile game Mr Nibbles Forever which is far too long. I apologise to people who have been asking me for a new version. I took on a few paid freelance projects a few months ago and they took up a whole bunch of time then I decided to take a full time position up in Perth a month ago which <a href="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/uncategorized/started-work-at-thebroth-in-perth/">drastically cut down my Mr Nibbles development time</a> sadly.</p>
<p>If you follow my <a href="https://trello.com/b/Ic11WQzF/mr-nibbles-forever">public Trello development board</a> however you can see that I have been working in the intervening time, just not as fast as the earlier development:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/2015-06-18_15-22-50.png"><img src="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/2015-06-18_15-22-50-1024x525.png" alt="2015-06-18_15-22-50" width="940" height="482" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-5599" /></a></p>
<p>In total there is something like 70 hours worth of my time that has gone into this release:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/2015-06-18_15-21-12.png"><img src="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/2015-06-18_15-21-12.png" alt="2015-06-18_15-21-12" width="280" height="772" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5598" /></a></p>
<p>Although 70 hours doesnt sound like all that much I think that this release contains more changes than any other. As hinted in the last release and other posts, I now have an artist on the project, <a href="https://twitter.com/woodystables">Woody Stables</a> who has helped totally transform the in-game backgrounds, the outfits, the effects and many other aspects of the game:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/2015-06-19_07-54-53.png"><img src="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/2015-06-19_07-54-53-1024x575.png" alt="2015-06-19_07-54-53" width="940" height="528" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-5602" /></a><br />
<a href="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/2015-06-17_20-46-28.jpg"><img src="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/2015-06-17_20-46-28-1024x766.jpg" alt="2015-06-17_20-46-28" width="940" height="703" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-5606" /></a><br />
<a href="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/2015-06-19_07-54-14.jpg"><img src="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/2015-06-19_07-54-14-1024x576.jpg" alt="2015-06-19_07-54-14" width="940" height="529" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-5604" /></a><br />
<a href="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/2015-06-19_07-54-30.jpg"><img src="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/2015-06-19_07-54-30-1024x576.jpg" alt="2015-06-19_07-54-30" width="940" height="529" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-5603" /></a></p>
<p>So now there are 13 different outfits in the game which you can win by spinning the wheel. They all look different and awesome but still stick to the same cutesy Mr Nibbles art style. Some of them come with cool and interesting effects as the below video shows:</p>
<p><iframe width="854" height="510" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aN5S0zMux30" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>You will also notice (if you have your sound turned on) that the game also now has a whole bunch more sound effects. That&#8217;s entirely thanks to <a href="https://twitter.com/watkinsonic">Joe Watkins</a> who I recruited to help out with the audio on the game. I think the audio really lifts the game up and adds so much more value to the different outfits and is often an overlooked but valuable part of games making.</p>
<p>The game really has started to take its final shape in my opinion but there is the problem. At the moment it has mostly only been my opinion of the game which has shaped its development. I have had a few testers play the game throughout its development and im very grateful for that but now its getting to the point where I need to test in earnest. </p>
<p>I am also very aware of the fact that I need to concentrate on marketing the game much more. At the moment the game is only really visible to a small number of people, people who read this blog, people who are members of the facebook page and people who I have met and talked to about the game. If I want the game to succeed and not get swallowed on the App Store then I need to step up my game in that department.</p>
<p>I have been doing a lot of reading about indie game marketing and have discovered <a href="http://vgamemarketing.com/">some valuable resources</a>. Its a massive daunting task but I have spoken to some other people who have done it and they have given me some great advice which has helped immensely. </p>
<p>So the next few weeks for me will be less about development and more about testing the game and building the things to help promote the game (websites, trailers, presskit etc).</p>
<p>If you would like to try the game out then as usual just <a href="mailto:mike.cann@gmail.com">send me an email</a> if you are on iOS or <a href="https://plus.google.com/communities/100690884724496136044?gclid=CJSZo8WqgsACFVZwvAodlo0AHQ&#038;dclid=CODB18WqgsACFVQZvAodWV4ATQ">send a request to join this google group</a> if you are on Android and ill hook you up!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/mr-nibbles-forever/mr-nibbles-alpha-8/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mr Nibbles Forever Update</title>
		<link>/mr-nibbles-forever/mr-nibbles-forever-update/</link>
		<comments>/mr-nibbles-forever/mr-nibbles-forever-update/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 10:02:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Cann]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Mr Nibbles Forever]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.mikecann.co.uk/?p=5580</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Its been a while since a Mr Nibbles Forever update. To be honest I haven&#8217;t actually done a whole lot coding wise on the project since the last update. I have been busy on other projects while I searched for an Artist and Audio guy to help on the project. Well im happy to say<p><a href="/mr-nibbles-forever/mr-nibbles-forever-update/">Continue Reading &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Its been a while since a Mr Nibbles Forever update. To be honest I haven&#8217;t actually done a whole lot coding wise on the project since the last update. I have been busy on other projects while I searched for an Artist and Audio guy to help on the project. Well im happy to say I have now found a couple of excellent guys to help me out so I have started to do some more work on the project.</p>
<p>Its not ready for a new release yet but for now you can see some of the new pretty art <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p><a href="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/2015-05-03_18-06-08.png"><img src="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/2015-05-03_18-06-08-1024x642.png" alt="2015-05-03_18-06-08" width="940" height="589" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-5582" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/2015-05-03_18-06-46.png"><img src="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/2015-05-03_18-06-46-1024x637.png" alt="2015-05-03_18-06-46" width="940" height="585" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-5583" /></a></p>
<p>Its nice isnt it? </p>
<p>We also have some cool new outfits in the pipeline:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Miner.jpg"><img src="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Miner-1024x181.jpg" alt="Miner" width="940" height="166" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-5584" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/firestarter.jpg"><img src="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/firestarter-1024x181.jpg" alt="firestarter" width="940" height="166" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-5585" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/disco.jpg"><img src="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/disco-1024x181.jpg" alt="disco" width="940" height="166" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-5586" /></a></p>
<p>Stay tuned for a playable release soon!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/mr-nibbles-forever/mr-nibbles-forever-update/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mr Nibbles Forever &#8211; Alpha 7</title>
		<link>/mr-nibbles-forever/mr-nibbles-forever-alpha-7/</link>
		<comments>/mr-nibbles-forever/mr-nibbles-forever-alpha-7/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2015 03:31:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Cann]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Mr Nibbles Forever]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2d]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[everyplay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Game]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[highscores]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mr nibbles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Update]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.mikecann.co.uk/?p=5565</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Well i&#8217;m now 8 weeks into development of Mr Nibbles Forever and I can safely say that the game is now feature complete (this probably should be Beta 1 release then not Apha 7 but oh well :P). I didn&#8217;t do a release last week as I had quite a bit of other work on<p><a href="/mr-nibbles-forever/mr-nibbles-forever-alpha-7/">Continue Reading &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well i&#8217;m now 8 weeks into development of Mr Nibbles Forever and I can safely say that the game is now feature complete (this probably should be Beta 1 release then not Apha 7 but oh well :P). I didn&#8217;t do a release last week as I had quite a bit of other work on and so there wasn&#8217;t all that much progress so I thought I would skip a week.</p>
<p>In this release:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/this-week.png"><img src="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/this-week.png" alt="this-week" width="679" height="918" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5567" /></a></p>
<p>Thats all from my <a href="https://trello.com/b/Ic11WQzF/mr-nibbles-forever">Trello board</a> for the project, the numbers are the amount of time I spent on each one (red is time taken, blue is estimate)</p>
<p>Before I get into some of the details you can see some of the new stuff in this video:</p>
<p><iframe width="1280" height="750" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0NR5bTPx15k" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>As you can see I have added a couple more particle effects and a new power up, the double jump. This meant changing some of the chunks so the player could not jump out of the world. I also added some &#8220;secret&#8221; areas that the player cant get to unless they have the double jump.</p>
<p>I have also added fruit to the game and &#8220;fruit collection&#8221; challenges. I have placed fruit in strategic locations in some of the chunks. These locations are often alternate routes to the normal one and are harder to get to, so you take a risk getting to them. I haven&#8217;t decided what to do with the fruit when a challenge isn&#8217;t currently active, for now I have just made it so that a fruit is worth 5 nibbles, let me know what you think!</p>
<p>In this release I have also added the Everyplay game recording service. I use this service to record every run in the game, then give the player the option to watch and share it. Hopefully this will encourage social engagement and drive new players to the game and encourage existing players to play more. I introduce this to the player when you complete the first challenge:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/IMG_01631.png"><img src="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/IMG_01631-1024x768.png" alt="IMG_0163[1]" width="940" height="705" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-5569" /></a></p>
<p>If you click watch replay then the Everyplay service starts up:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/IMG_01641.png"><img src="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/IMG_01641-1024x768.png" alt="IMG_0164[1]" width="940" height="705" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-5570" /></a></p>
<p>You can even provide a narration to your video using the front facing camera (click to watch)! </p>
<p><a href="https://everyplay.com/videos/14904453"><img src="http://www.mikecann.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/2015-03-14_11-32-10.png" alt="2015-03-14_11-32-10" width="711" height="438" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5575" /></a></p>
<p>I also added IAP so you can purchase outfits if you don&#8217;t have the patience to collect the nibbles and spin the week. There is also high scores in there now for iOS that uses Game Center.</p>
<p>So the game is pretty much done now apart from the missing artwork and audio. I have been speaking to various Artists and audio people for a few weeks now so hopefully things should start to come together by next week.</p>
<p>As usual if you would like to test out the iOS version just shoot me an email: mike.cann@gmail.com or if you are on Android then join <a href="https://plus.google.com/communities/100690884724496136044">this community</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/mr-nibbles-forever/mr-nibbles-forever-alpha-7/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
